[Music]
welcome to this business Central launch
event video about what's next in Alo for
GitHub my name is Freddy Christensen I'm
a technical evangelist out of Micosoft
Copenhagen and I'm here to tell you
about like where are we going in the
near future I usually have a few slides
about this in my launch event uh video
as the last thing and I usually have
like a disclaimer saying no promises no
dates when I looked at this like agenda
says listen to partner feedback uh
follow new security recommendations and
other things saying no promises kind of
sounds like that would be wrong we
definitely need to listen to partner
feedback we definitely need to follow
new security recommendations so some of
these things are musthaves some of these
things are stuff that we are definitely
going to do but I can't give you a date
yet but anyway let's have a look at new
security
recommendations and I don't have any
specifics here but um the the evil words
of the past is why mess with stuff that
works like growing up in the 80s that
was what we said like if it works don't
fix it today it's a different world like
Microsoft spends billions of dollars
every year on security
and and they impose all of these
findings and security on all the teams
inside of Microsoft we every single
month get stuff that we have to
implement in our devops pipelines in our
devops system in order to make sure that
we are secure and our products are
secure for our customers to use them now
ALG goo for GitHub will benefit from all
of these Investments and provide a
secure and reliable platform for
partners to use and that is one of the
reasons why you should bet on a go for
GitHub one of the things we've been
working on for quite some while is
indirect templates and customizations um
there's a PR open on that has been open
for quite some time there's a few
partners that are actually testing out
this as we
go what the feature is going I I
actually think I've talked about this
feature uh last year in the launch event
video as something that is coming but
now I think we are closer to actually
being able to to deliver this it's going
to allow for indirect or potentially
private templates for your repository
now if you're a partner and you want to
to create uh customer specific uh
customizations of a specific kind for a
specific type of customer you might even
have a an indirect template for for this
category of customers or another
template for your appsource apps where
you have some of your set settings some
of your custom jobs custom steps uh
built into that template so you don't
have to do any modifications on the
final
repositories um it's quite a big PR U
but but it's all about the update ELO
system files that will run and and be
able to merge custom jobs and custom
steps into uh into into your uh
templates and then into your
repositories I think the final thing we
need in this one is figuring out exactly
what we do with settings because like
default settings we want to be able to
to specify those in the indirect
template also and that doesn't really
work with the current PR so there's a
few few hours of work to go there but
but I expect this one to to make it in
in probably April or
May I said no dates oh I just gave a
date I expect that okay we want to find
analyze new get support so new get
support what's missing there well two
things comes to mind generate and
publish runtime packages as new get uh
that part is something that I very
frequently hear from Partners they miss
a a a an efficient way of doing that and
the second thing we need is more testing
more adoption more roll out we need all
Partners to publish their apps as net to
share with other partners that is big on
the agenda for Al go for GitHub in the
future another thing we're working on is
running tests and Page scripting tests
on online
environments um in this release we have
released a functionality that can
publish test and test apps and stuff
like that to online environments we also
want to be able to specify when
publishing to a Sandbox that you want to
run the tests or maybe run the scripting
test so when publishing to a QA
environment where customer needs to to
do the final testing on your app you can
run all the page scripting tests as part
of your cicd not part of the cicd
pipeline probably but part of the
publishing effort uh either as
continuous deployment or as manual
deployment um and then running all the
the the page scripting tests making sure
that all all the recorded tests Works
before actually spending time on testing
the functionality uh of your your Fe
your your features move away from BC
container hel I've talked about this a
few times as well and we're getting
closer and closer we will be moving away
from BC from using BC container helper
in Al go for GitHub right now BC
container helpers is a huge pile of cool
functionality that a lot of partners are
using for all kinds of things um what
we're going to do is we're we're not
going to remove BC container helper from
the power shell gallery or anything like
that but we are going to stop supporting
it at some point in time until that date
what we're going to do is we're going to
take devops relevant features and
Implement those in probably Powershell
modules that will be part of
Alo or GitHub actions or whatever and
then algo will stop using container
helper for these things uh there there's
a long way probably two three years
before we we're going to get through
with all of these
things um but we at this time we
we seriously uh recommend that Partners
move to a managed devop solution if they
have if if partners are running right
now A devop solution that they're
managing themselves based on BC
container Helper and and the cicd
Hands-On lab they will at some point in
time have a lot of work to do in order
to to to get going on a new platform um
today moving to algo for GitHub or
another managed devop solution might not
be as big of a change as as you think
thanks for watching the video and see
you next time